<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on mcstatistics</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on mcstatistics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Marlon Schumacher &amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Equation Modeling in R</title>
      <link>/post/structural-equation-modeling-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/structural-equation-modeling-in-r/</guid>
      <description>lavaan: A Package for SEM Syntax for Modelling Model Fitting (Standardized) Estimated Parameter Change Visualization Sampling Weights   lavaan: A Package for SEM In my pervious post I made a short introduction to Structural Equation Modeling (SEM). But now it’s about using R for SEM. However, to use R for SEM we need the package lavaan. For the visualization of the models we also need the package semPlot. As you probably know already the installation of the packages is very simple: install.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Equation Modeling: A Short Introduction</title>
      <link>/post/structural-equation-modeling-a-short-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/structural-equation-modeling-a-short-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Introduction &amp;amp; Advantages There are a lot of variations regarding Structural Equation Modeling (SEM). Therefore, this article is focusing on the basics of SEM. Fundamentally, SEM can be classified as a combination of path analysis and confirmatory factor analysis. With SEM and path analysis you will have a big felxibility for specifying relationships between theoretical constructs. For example, it is possible to postulate rather complex models that may include a single construct that is theorized to be a predictor of some constructs and is also predicted by other constructs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>